Guide to the Robert Evans Alexander papers, 1935-1993
Alexander, Robert Evans papers, 1935-1993
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert Evans Alexander papers, 1935-1993
3087
Robert Evans Alexander, 1907-
86.4 cubic ft.
Contains architectural plans and drawings, reports, correspondence, legal papers, agenda and minutes of meetings, printed material, negative microfilm, cassette tape, photographs, drawings, and slides.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes architectural plans and drawings, reports, correspondence, legal papers, agenda and minutes of meetings, printed material and photographs from the firms of Neutra and Alexander, and Alexander and Associates. Projects include a plan for various buildings and schools. Also, "Checkpoint Charlie," a volume of personal reminiscences; "Convicts with AIDS," and "Why L.A.?;" and obituary material.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
An architect and city planner, Robert Evans Alexander graduated in the Cornell University Class of 1930. He was a member of the International Fraternity of Lambda Alpha, Los Angeles Chapter.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes architectural plans and drawings, reports, correspondence, legal papers, agenda and minutes of meetings, printed material and photographs from the firms of Neutra and Alexander, and Alexander and Associates. Projects include a plan for various buildings in the Territory of Guam; various schools including Palos Verdes High School, Adelphi College (Garden City, N.Y.), Simpson College (Indianola, Iowa), the University of California at San Diego, and California Institute of Technology (Behavioral Biology Laboratory); the Los Angeles County Hall of Records; buildings at various military bases; the visitors' building and cyclorama at Gettysburg National Military Park; and Bunker Hill Residential Towers (Los Angeles). Also, "Checkpoint Charlie," a volume of personal reminiscences, 1989; "Convicts with AIDS" (1992), and "Why L.A.?" (1993); and obituary material.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Alexander, Robert Evans, 1907-; Neutra, Richard.; Neutra and Alexander.; Alexander and Associates.; Adelphi College--Buildings.; Simpson College--Buildings.; University of California, San Diego--Buildings.; California Institute of Technology--Buildings.; Palos Verdes High School.; Los Angeles County Hall of Records.; Gettysburg National Military Park.; Bunker Hill Residential Towers (Los Angeles, Calif.); Lambda Alpha International. Los Angeles Chapter.
Subjects:
AIDS (Disease).; Campus planning.; City planning.; Architecture.; City planners.; Architects.
Places:
Guam.
Form and Genre Terms:
Drawings.; Minutes.; Photographs.; Color slides.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Brochure describing the firm, and listing projects of all kinds accomplished by the firm (Box 1-2)
- "Preview of a New Way of Life" (Box 1-2)
  An article written for Revere Copper & Brass, shortly after Pearl Harbor
- "The Architect and Society" (Box 1-2)
  An outline of some thoughts on the future of the profession
- "Southern California Transit - Tragic Blunder or Blessed Boon? (Box 1-2)
- "The Beautiful Valley" (Box 1-2)
  A brief statement given on the final presentation of the Vista General Plan
- "Design Objectives in City Planning" (Box 1-2)
  From a seminar at 1955 A.I.A. Convention
- "It's Time to Look at Tomorrow's Schools" (Box 1-2)
  A talk given to California School Administrators in 1958
- "Designing for Science at Orange Coast College" (Box 1-2)
  Account of planning and investigation which applies to a planning approach in general
- "Re: Planning a Campus" (Box 1-2)
  The reproduction of an internal memorandum as a guide for planning
- "A Tip on a Sure Winner at 100 to 1 Odds" (Box 1-2)
  Attempted guide to college planning
- "Return to our Cities" (Box 1-2)
  Statement to the Southern California Chapter, American Institute of Architects
- "West End Urban Renewal" (Box 1-2)
  Brief report on Stockton, California's Redevelopment Project
- "Reading the Palm of Escondido" (Box 1-2)
  A brief report on a general plan, for popular consumption
- "Community Planning and Housing for the Pallikkaranai project, Madras, India." (Box 1-2)
- "Anchorage at the Crossroads" (Box 1-2)
  Aug. 1964 brief report on the re-planning of Anchorage after the earthquake
- "Fall-Out Shelter Survey, Contra Costa County, California" (Box 1-2)
  In two parts: Part 1 is an actual summary of results of the survey, and Part 2 describes in detail the procedures and operating experience
- "A New Look for the City." (Box 1-2)
  About half of this book written in collaboration with Drayton Bryant, was published by the Haynes Foundation under the title "Rebuilding a City"
- "Long Range Development Plan - University of California, San Diego, Oct. 1963" (Box 1-2)
  First plan for one of three new University campuses to accomodate 27,500 students each in California
- "Planning for Guam" (Box 1-2)
  Represents the first attempt at a regional plan for the newly formed territory of Guam
- "San Mateo Junior College" (Box 1-2)
  Very small manuscript on planning a community college
- "Report on a Development Plan and a Construction Program for Orange Coast College" (Box 1-2)
- "Master Plan for Adelphi College, Garden City, Long Island" (Box 1-2)
  Reproduction in rough form of the dummy for a brochure
- "St. John's College Development Plan" (Box 1-2)
- "A Plan for the Tulsa Central Business District" (Box 1-2)
  Script for a taped talk accompanied by slides, explaining the CBD plan for Tulsa
- "A Plan for Central Tulsa" (Box 1-2)
- "Urban Design Manual of Goals" (Box 1-2)
  Guide for plan preparation and implementation for the San Diego Border Area Program
- "An Architect Views the Client's Role in School Building Planning" (Box 1-2)
- 8 page reprint of "The People of Sacramento - Plan for 1960 Through Redevelopment" (Sacramento City Planning Commission) (Box 1-2)
- Baldwin Hills Elementary School, Los Angeles (Box 3)
  Photos of buildings
- University Elementary School (UCLA) (Box 3)
- Pierce Residence, REA (Box 3)
  Photos of living room interior
- Photos of a church interior; not labeled, c. 1951 (Box 3)
- St. Johns - torn page with note about brochure, February 1955 (Box 3)
- Orange Coast College - Photos of plans and buildings, undated (Box 3-4)
  Photos of buildings, sketches, and plans for buildings; some people
- Pallikaranai Project, India, undated (Box 4)
- Correspondence on Guam and Lawsuit Material (N & A) (Box 5-6)
- Correspondence on Guam and Lawsuit Material (N & A;) (Box 6-7)
- Correspondence on Guam and Lawsuit Material (N & A;) (Box 8-9)
- Karachi (Cost Estimates, etc.) (Box 9-10)
- Claremont Methodist Church; Christ Episcopal Church - Ontario; Santa Ana Police Facilities Bldg.; Mail Analysis N & A; Apr. 13, 1959 to Mar. 12, 1959, including REA Mail Analysis 1959 (Box 11-12)
- Contra Costa; REA Personal 1957-1958; Tulsa (Box 12-13)
- Hall of Records (Studies) (Box 13)
- Miramar Chapel; Riviera Methodist Church; San Fernando State College (Box 13-15)
- Ticktocker Nursery (1); Riviera Shop Drawings (1)-Code Requirements, etc.; Intermediate School-Alamitos (1); Office Filing - HTW; U.S. Embassy - Karachi (1) (Box 15-16)
- Karachi - Embassy Building (Box 17-18)
- Alamitos So. School; Alamitos Multi-Use Building (Box 18)
- Palos Verdes; United Auto Workers (Box 18-19)
- Hall of Records (All 'A' Files plus 2 'C' Files) (Box 19-20)
- Hall of Records (All 'B' Files) (Box 20-21)
- Mountain Home AFB Add. Housing A2-Corr. Client USAF, A3-Corr. Collaborators HH & J;, B4-Minutes of Meetings (Box 20-21)
- Mountain Home 820 Unites (1 file) (Box 20-21)
- National Charity League - B9 - Change Orders & Reduction in Sound from Equipment Rm. (61/62) (Box 20-21)
- Observation Nursery School (1957 - 1 file; UCLA Kindergarten Nursery Stae II-C-1 Corr. Client; C-2 Corr. State Agencies (Box 20-21)
- Central Union Elementary School (Lemoore), Gettysburg A & B; Files (Box 21-22)
- Gettysburg - C Files (Box 22-23)
- Fine Arts Building, University of Nevada, Reno (Box 23-24)
- Adelphi College (Box 25)
- Adelphi College - Library (Box 25-26)
- (See REA Job List) REA Jobs (Box 26-27)
- (See REA Job List) REA Jobs (Box 27-28)
- Lemoore NAS; Lemoore "500"; Lemoore Akers School (Box 28-29)
- Simpson Dormitories (Box 29-30)
- Simpson Dormitories, Simpson Library A-A1A, C1 to C3B (Box 29-30)
- Simpson Library fr. C-3 to C-14-1 (Box 30-31)
- Painted Desert Community; Houses First Increment; Second Increment - Comm. - Maintenance - Trailer Park & Fred Harvey (Box 31-32)
- International Student Center (Box 32-33)
- Cornell LRDP; The Breakers; South America Alliance for Progress (Box 34)
- Escondido; Stockton; Anchorage, Alaska (Box 35-36)
- Griffith Starland (Mt. Hollywood); Campen Theatre (Navy) (Box 36)
- REA - Speeches, Seminars, etc. 1947-1961 (Box 36-37)
- UCSD Residence Halls, Unit 1 and CFB (A,B,C Files; CFB Step 2-A1, B; M1' Res. Halls Step 2 - A1, B1, M1; College II; Library (Box 37-38)
- UCSD Residence Halls, Unit 1 and CFB (from C2 files) (Box 38-39)
- UCSD - LRDP A through B9 (Box 39-40)
- UCSD - LRDP B-10 through B-15 plus Agenda Books & Brochure (Box 40-41)
- UCSD - LRDP B-1 through B-1-H (Box 41-42)
- UCSD - LRDP VI-i through B-1BB (Box 42-43)
- Mail Analysis N & A; 1960-1963; Mail Analysis REA 1964-1965; Mail Charge Out Sheets 1959-1965 (Box 43-44)
- State of California Environmental Quality & Amenities (Box 44-45)
- El Paso; Vista (Box 45-46)
- AIA Files; Committee on Advancement of the Profession (5); 1956 Convention; 1961 Convention; NW Reg. Conf. & Houston Conv.; Western Mountain Region 11th Annual Convention; Convention Mex. San Diego Chapter Mtd.; Community Planning Comm. Kit; Border Planning Commission (40 Misc. Publications) (Box 46-47)
- Personal 1964-1965 (2); Misc. 1965-1968 (4) (Box 47)
- Misc. by others than REA Nov. 1965 - Dec. 31, 1968 (Box 47)
- Misc. Corresp. with SOM ( Oct. 1960 - June 1964) (Box 47)
- I.O.M General Nov. 1965 - Dec. 1968; Staff Meetings; University Club; Cornell General 1968; Cornell - Delta Phi; USC School of Architecture Fifth Year Design 1961-1962; Competitions, Exhibits; Competition, Washington University, St. Louis, Missouri; Governors Mansion Competition 1961; Publicity & Regional Plan Assoc. 1966 & 1967. (Box 47)
- Regional Planning Association of Southern California, University of Nevada Library, Rand Corporation, and Guam. (Box 48)
- Mail Analysis 1966-1969 (REA; N & A; 1964; Mail Out Sheets 1966-1969) (Box 49)
- Town Hall - General & Speakers 1964-1967; Town Hall Board of Governors 1966 & Printed Matter (Box 49-50)
- Proposition 2 UCSD; FDR Memorial; Exhibits, Competition (N & A;) 1959-1960; N & A; Bldgs. in LA & Vicinity; IOM-RJN 1961; IOM RJN General 1959 - 1962 N & A; Glendale Building; General Cost Data N & A; Job Deadline N & A; Misc. 1959-1961; Former Employees 1952-1964 (2) (Box 49-50)
- UCSD Basic Sciences A7 B Files & TV File (Box 51)
- Bunker Hill Towers A1 through 8D correspondence (Box 52)
- Bunker Hill Towers correspondence, planning info., cost estimates (Box 53)
- Bunker Hill Towers A8C through B9 & Hotel Prospect; outline specifications; correspondence; weekly progress reports (Box 53-54)
- Bunker Hill Towers C1 through C3B; correspondence - contractors and consultants (Box 54-55)
- Bunker Hill Towers C3C through C9; lab tests; change orders; bids, etc. (Box 55-56)
- Bunker Hill Towers C10 though C17 & Newspaper Clippings; correspondence - consultants and others (Box 56-57)
- Bunker Hill Hotel A-1 through B1A; cost estimates; minutes of meetings; fine arts; air conditioning; parking needs (Box 57-58)
- Bunker Hill Hotel B-2 through B-6 & Newspapers clippings; AIA -Southern California Chapter - Correspondence 1966-1969; REA President - Correspondence 1970; Speakers for Meetings - Correspondence. (Box 58)
- Agendas & Minutes of Meetings 1969; REA President - 1970; Correspondence 1970 - REA Pres., Misc. Committees; 1970 Newspaper clippings and articles; 1970 LA General Plan; AIA Filing (Misc. Corresp. 1970), Watts Enterprises - Corresp. & Interoffice Memos; Mail Analysis 1970; Mailout Sheets 1970; Mobile Building 1960-1969; Misc. Corresp. 1969; Progressive Architecture 1959-1969; School Executive from 1959; House & Home 1959-1961; REA Competitions & Exhibits 1967-1969; Misc. Job Files; Building Center Exhibit 1967; Comm. for Economic Development; Mt. Home Air Force Base Housing USAF ( 1957); Mt. Home Add. Housing A-1 Negotiation. (Box 58-59 & 60 (oversize))
- Caltech Master Planning Studies & Plans, 1975, 1985 (Box 65)
- UCSD Residence Hall as built-in ozalids (Box 66)
- Planning reports (published) for University of California at San Diego; California Institute of Technology; Los Angeles Central Business District; City of Escondido, California; Stockton, California; Norwalk, California; and State of California Transportation Agency (Box 67)
- Claremont College Parking Presentation (Box 68)
- Specs Married Student Housing, U.S.C., Simpson Library, Army Family Housing at Yuma Test Station, Capehart Quarters Project Ashmi (Box 68)
- News clips on practice (Neutra & Alexander and REA); Neutra & Alexander - specs for G.W.H.S. (Box 68)
- Bradbury Bldg. material; Bankunst & Werkform, REA studies, consulting, correspondence, sketches, company brochures, and tapes. (M.B. Jackson "Instant Transit" microfilm - Desert Counseling Clinic, album of articles, photo clipping album, clippings, negatives of Tulsa Rept, photo albums, F.H.A. Com. corresp. (Box 69)
- Claremont College - planning files (Box 70)
- Files on Cal Tech Behavioral Biology Labs (Box 71-72)
- News clipping scrapbooks - (Box 73 (leg.3))
  Guam in 1952, 1 entry; Motivation Rept. by Alexander and Sarma in Competition for All-India Institute of Medical Science (Placed Second)
- Pre- 1975 specifications (Box 74-77)
- Pre- 1975 specifications Bunker Hill Towers specs, Buildings C-E (Box 78)
- Pre- 1975 specifications Bank of America specs (Box 79)
- Pre-1975 specifications (Box 80)
- Palos Verdes High School, Great Western Savings, Karachi Embassy, Gettysburg Visitors Center, Bunker Hill area feasibility report, 1951; photo taken from Bunker Hill Towers by J. Amestoy, 1973. (Box 81 (o/s 3"))
- Humanities and S.S. bldg. at Cal Tech, Distinguished honor award and The Breakers material, Santa Ana Police Bldg., Capehart Quarters Ashmi Naval Air Station (Box 82 (o/s 3"))
- Pre-1975 specifications, U.S. Embassy Karachi, Gettysburg Visitors Center, Univ. of Cal. School of Sci. & Engineering, Residence Hall I (Box 83 (o/s 3"))
- Pre- 1975 San Diego specifications, Palos Verdes H.S., Carson City Hall, Bank of America (Box 84 (o/s 3"))
- Awards and old architectural journals, Great Western Savings - Architects Rept., Mt. Hollywood Study, Westwood International Student's Center (Box 85 (o/s 3"))
- Anchorage renderings, Adelphi and St. John's brochures (Box 86 (o/s 3"))
- Roll of Palos Verdes High School plans (Box 87)
- Roll of Carson City Hall and Community Center plans (Box 89)
- Tube carton - Page Residence (Box 91)
- Claremont College - Consulting 1972-1975 (Box 92)
- Claremont College - Housing (Job 7122) 1972-1975 (Box 92)
- Claremont College - Joint Campus Plan Committee 1972-1975 (Box 92)
- Cornell University - General 1978-1979 (Box 92)
- Cornell University - Library Material List 1978 (Box 92)
- Transit System - Financing 1979-1971 (Box 92)
- Transit System - Financing 1971-1973 (Box 92)
- Los Angeles Central Business District (CBD) Transit File 1969-1973 (Box 92)
- Instant Transit 1969-1971 (Box 92)
- Rapid Transit 1967-1971 (Box 92)
- Reading File (binders of chron. outgoing correspondence) 1974-1978 (Box 92)
- Photographs
  - Bunker Hill Hotel and Residential Towers (Box 93)
  - Elysian Park Hights, Los Angeles (Box 93)
  - International Student Center, UCLA (Box 93)
  - Library, University of Nevada, Reno (Box 93)
  - Neil Jacoby International Student Center, UCLA (Box 93)
  - Meadowsbrook Park, San Bernardino Valley (Box 93)
  - Palms Park Community Center and Library (Box 93)
  - Lincoln Park High School, Shops Building, Los Angeles (Box 93)
  - Santa Ysabel Indian Mission Museum (Box 93)
  - Hazard Park Recreation Center (Box 93)
  - Micellaneous Projects (Box 93)
  - Noyes Chemical-Physical Lab (Box 93)
  - Solar Hot Water Heating System (Box 93)
  - Los Angeles Community College Cultural Center (Box 93)
  - Ramo Hall, CIT (Box 93)
  - General Services Building, UC San Diego (Box 93)
  - Base Theater, Camp Pendleton (Box 93)
  - Speech Arts Building, Orange Coast College (Box 93)
  - Humanities Building, CIT (Box 93)
  - Anchorage, Alaska (Box 93)
  - Baldwin Hills (Box 93)
  - Bank of America, San Bernardino Valley (Box 93)
  - Basic Science Building, Medical School, UC San Diego (Box 93)
  - Baxter Hall, CIT (Box 93)
  - Hidden Hills Elementary School (Box 93)
  - North Fontana Park (Box 93)
  - UCLA (Box 93)
  - UCLA Elementary School (Box 93)
  - Residence Halls, UC San Diego (Box 93)
- Photographs and negatives, some bound reports
  - UC San Diego (Box 94)
  - University City (Box 94)
  - National Charity League Observation Nursery School, Los Angeles (Box 94)
  - National Opera House, Sydney, Australia (Box 94)
  - Adelphi College, Long Island (Box 94)
  - Germany Trip, 1965 (Box 94)
  - Miscellaneous Letters, Documents (Box 94)
  - Professional Records (personal photographs, copy of birth certificate, etc.) (Box 94)
  - Clippings (Box 94)
  - Reports (Box 94)
  - Central Union Elementary School, Lemoore, California (Box 94)
  - Firm (Robert Alexander & Richard Neutra) profile book (Box 94)
  - Library, University of Nevada, Reno (Box 94)
  - Mono County Courthouse (Box 94)
  - Ruberoid Competition (Box 94)
  - UCLA Kindergarten (Box 94)
  - Homes for Military Personnel (Box 94)
  - Baldwin Hills (Box 95)
  - Bank of America - San Bernardino (Box 95)
  - Bank of America - Whittier (Box 95)
  - Beverly Drive Country Club (Box 95)
  - Alexander Home, Mammoth Lakes, California (Box 95)
  - Anchorage, Alaska (Box 95)
  - USC - housing (Box 95)
  - UC San Diego (Box 95)
  - Los Angeles Public Library (correspondence, plans, photographs) (Box 95)
- Photographs, reports, and job files
  - Central Library, Los Angeles (Box 96)
  - Ocean Park, Santa Monica (Box 96)
  - Orchard Gables (Box 96)
  - San Diego Border Area Program (Box 96)
  - New Horizons Unlimited (Box 96)
  - Pearce Residence (Box 96)
  - Pallikkaranai (Box 96)
  - Mt. Hollywood (Box 96)
  - Mono County Courthouse (Box 96)
  - Mutual Savings & Loan, Pasadena (Box 96)
  - The Breakers, Laguna Beach (Box 96)
  - International Student Center (Westwood), UCLA (Box 96)
  - Haynes Foundation (Box 96)
  - Great Western Savings & Loan, Gardena (Box 96)
  - S. California Gas Company (Box 96)
  - Grape St. School (Box 96)
  - General Electric (Box 96)
  - FDR Memorial (Box 96)
  - El Paso (Box 96)
  - Escondido (Box 96)
  - Carson City Hall (Box 96)
  - Catskill Ave. School (Box 96)
  - Claremont Colleges (Box 96)
  - Humanities Building, CIT (Box 96)
  - Campen Theater, Camp Pendleton (Box 96)
  - Court of Man, CIT (Box 96)
  - Cal Poly - SLO - Student Health Center (Box 96)
  - Report: Wherry Act Housing Project, Mountain Home, Ind. (Box 96)
  - Royal Pacific Hotel, Honolulu (Box 96)
  - Los Angeles County Hall of Records (Box 96)
  - Elysian Park Heights, Los Angeles (Box 96)
  - St. John's College, Annapolis, Md. (Box 96)
  - Study: Elements of Secondary Schools (Box 96)
  - San Mateo Jr. College (Box 96)
- Reports & Bound Photographs
  - San Mateo Jr. College (Box 97)
  - Sacramento (Box 97)
  - Simpson College, Indianola (Box 97)
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, Los Angeles (Box 97)
  - Painted Desert (Box 97)
  - C.A. Empresas Electricas, Venezuela (Box 97)
  - San Pedro Community Hotel (Box 97)
  - Chapel - Miramar Naval Air Station, San Diego (Box 97)
  - Tamare - Business Center and Theater, Venezuela (Box 97)
  - Santa Ana Civic Center (Box 97)
  - Science Building, Orange Coast College (Box 97)
  - Planning for Guam (Box 97)
  - Riviera Methodist Church (Box 97)
  - Ontario Episcopal Church (Box 97)
  - Trebol Scheme I (Box 97)
  - Miscellaneous Photostats and Awards (Box 97)
  - Baldwin Hill photostats (Box 97)
  - Binders of clippings (each containing a list of articles): Publicity 1939, 1944, 1957-1962; Publicity 1963-1967; Publicity 1968-1969 (Box 97)
- Baldwin Hills; Estrada Courts, Los Angeles; Lakewood City; Parchest, Bronx (brochures), 1 (Box 98)
- Temple of Contemplation, NYC; Estrada Courts, Los Angeles; Baldwin Hills; Correspondence, notes 1930-1946; "Dear Joe" manuscript and published form (re futuristic city plan published in booklet by Revere Copper and Brass), 2 (Box 98)
- Publicity 1970 (clippings with listing), 3 (Box 98)
- Fact Sheets (A to O), 4 (Box 98)
- Fact Sheets (P to Z), 5 (Box 98)
- Fact Sheets/Project Descriptions, 6 (Box 98)
- Articles by Robert Alexander (Box 98)
- Report: "A New Look for the City: Los Angeles, 1950" (Box 98)
- Pamman Hotel, Saudi Arabia (Box 98)
- 1 spool neg. microfilm: Lincoln High School (Box 98)
- 1 spool neg. microfilm: Sheriff Headquarters, Bridgeport, CA (Box 98)
- 1 spool neg. microfilm: Health Center, San Luis Obispo, CA (Box 98)
- Briefs and Documents: R.E. Alexander vs. Board of Public Works, Los Angeles (Box 99)
- Scrapbook of clippings: Guam (Box 99)
- Album: Air Force Family Housing Proposal (primarily photographs) (Box 99)
- Album: Palakarni Project Pilot Farm, Madras, India (primarily photographs) (Box 99)
- Negatives: Pallikkaranai; Student Center, Orange Coast College; Haynes Foundation; UCLA (Box 99)
- Slides (partially labeled) subjects include: Anchorage, AK; Bunker Hill; Cornell; CIT Graphics Building; El Paso; England; Escondido; FDR Memorial; Hawaii; International Student Center; Karachi; Lemoore School; MRT; Mt. Hollywood; Reno Library; Orange Coast College; Painted Desert; UCLA Elementary; University of California, San Diego; UES. (Box 99)
- International Student Center (Box 100-101)
- Behavior Biology Lab, Cal Tech, Pasadena, CA; Convention Center Hotel, 1969 (Box 102)
- Bunker Hills Towers Site Plans, Sept. 1967 - Nov. 1967 (copies); California State Polytechnic College, San Luis Obispo Health Center Addition, 1973 (Box 103)
- California State Polytechnic College, San Luis Obispo Health Center Addition, 1973 (Box 104)
- City of Carson City Hall (Box 105)
- Preview of a New Way of Life, 1 (Box 107)
  Written 1942 for Revere Copper and Brass series on post-war speculations.
- San Diego Border Area Plan 1966, 2 (Box 107)
  After Tia Juana River was channelized, eliminating threat of flooding both sides of border, City of San Diego planned to develop both sides of delta area. It would have destroyed invaluable estuarine wetlands which I would never touch today.
- San Diego Area Plan: Urban Design Manual of Goals, 3 (Box 107)
- First Increment General Services & Cafeteria Building UCSD, 4 (Box 107)
- LRDP California Institute of Technology (Caltech), Nov. 1970, 5 (Box 107)
- Same, revised Nov. 1972., 6 (Box 107)
  Administration did not realize storm of protest would arise re possible expansion into surrounding residential areas & requested revision.
- Caltech Science for Mankind 1972-1973., 7 (Box 107)
  Fund-raising brochure prepared after architects selected & designs prepared.
- Design for Center for Holistic Healing prototype, Nov. 1975., 8 (Box 107)
- Master Plan Civic Center City of Carson 1972-1973., 9 (Box 107)
- Thriftimart Supermarket, Baldwin Hills Shopping Center 1947, 10 (Box 107)
- Baldwin Hills Village Data Book 1939 (BHV)., 11 (Box 107)
  Ed Merrill made many analyses, detailed here.
- BHV "Dope Sheets" (Then called 1000 Gardens), 1939., 12 (Box 107)
  Includes my first sketch for BHV as single family homes recalling my living experience at #1 Stanley Oval, Westfield, N.J. on cul-de-sac. Also statistical analysis & opening pamphlets, 1942.
- BHV in Pencil Points Magazine Sept. 1944, 13 (Box 107)